Kokil Singh

I am a hardworking, sincere person who has a voracious appetite for knowledge; Ever curious about anything and everything that I come across. This has led me to explore the world of research. While I love both my domains, the inter-disciplinary fields of Biological Sciences and Computer Science, viz., Bioinformatics, Computational Biology and Biomedical Engineering interest me the most.

Work History

2022-05 -2022-09

Summer Research Intern

CSIR-Central Electronics Engineering Research Institute (CSIR-CEERI), Pilani, RJ

Supervisor: Dr. Satyam Srivastava, Senior Scientist **Work involved:** Detection and classification of cervical intraepithelial neoplasia using ML models. Apart from that, I was entrusted to build a web-based dashboard to create an environment for patient-doctor interaction. Additionally, I also developed an Android App that is not only integrated with the patient dashboard but also supports the Classification ML model.

2022-05 -Current

Undergraduate Researcher

BITS Pilani, Hyderabad Campus, Hyderabad, TG

Supervisors: Dr. K.N. Mohan, Associate Professor,

Department of Biological Sciences & Dr. Lov Kumar,

Assistant Professor, Department of Computer

Science and Information Systems

(Ongoing)

The project involves development of a bioinformatics tool.

2022-01 -2022-05

Undergraduate Researcher

BITS Pilani, Hyderabad Campus, Hyderabad, TG **Supervisor:** Dr. Vivek Sharma, Assistant Professor,

Department of Biological Sciences

Project Title: Epigenetics of Brain Cancer

Work involved: Understanding various epigenetic

Contact

Address

Hyderabad, India

Phone

992 056 2969

E-mail

kokildeepti@gmail.com

Skills

Programming Languages: Python, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Java, C/C++

Python Libraries: TensorFlow/Keras, Numpy, Pandas, Streamlit, Scikit-Learn, OpenCV, Matplotlib

Other Tools/Frameworks: Firebase, Node.js, Express,js

Languages

English

Hindi

modifications and their underlying mechanisms, how they impact orchestration of processes such as transcription, repair, replication of DNA, how all of this manifests itself in glioblastoma and to find potential research topics.

Education

2020-08 -Current

M.Sc Biological Sciences and B.E. Computer Science

BITS Pilani, Hyderabad Campus - Hyderabad, TG CGPA: **9.416** (as of Sep 2022)

Awards

BITS Pilani Merit Scholarship

(Aug 2021 - Present)
Awarded to the top 1% students of the University

Lala Kailashpath Singhania Merit Scholarship (Jan 2020)

Awarded to the student with the most outstanding academic performance and an exemplary record in extra-curricular activities